

CONTACT

- +33 6 05 20 32 08
- ✓ david@aparicio.eu
- Q Lyon, France
- david.aparicio.eu

EDUCATION

2010 - 2013 INSA DE LYON (FRANCE)

 Master of Engineering Computer Science

2012 - 2014 UNICAMP (BRAZIL)

- Computer Engineering
- GPA: 3.2 / 4.0

SKILLS

- Cloud / DevOps
- Go / API / Microservices
- Python / Data / Al
- Design Data-Intensive apps
- Conference speaker & organizer
- Effective Communication
- Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- French (Fluent)
- Portuguese (Fluent)
- Spanish (Intermediate)

DAVID APARICIO

SENIOR DEVSECOPS ENGINNER

PROFILE

Go/Python Software Engineer. Throughout my career, I've gained valuable insights into security issues and the development of high-performance applications that handle large volumes of data. Additionally, I have experience SysAdmin activities, have dedicated over 4 years to being on-call.

I also share my knowledge and experiences through conference talks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

OVHcloud

DataOps

2019 - 2024

- Datalake Baremetal to Public Cloud migration (Terraform+Ansible).
 3K+ employees (+330TB of data, +42K tables, 85 data projects)
- Data industrialization, participation in performance & security audits.
- Monitor & automatic repair for the Data Ingestion pipelines (CDC).
- CIO Technical architect volunteer, EMEA Startup mentor since 2023.

Amadeus 2017 - 2019

DevSecOps consultant for Altran

- Datalake Open-Premise migration to Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
 17K+ employees (+200 nodes, 10k CPU, 84 TB of RAM, 13 PB of Data)
- Datalake migration from VMs to RedHat OpenShift Kubernetes.
- Migrate Puppet to Ansible, robust and resilient with Molecule tests.
- Implement Backup & Restore Kerberos to reduce this SPOF risk.

CNRS/LIRIS

2015-2017

PhD Fellowship

- Develop autoscaling real-time sentiment analysis using IaC and GitOps deployments over 4 cloud providers (AWS,GCP,OVH,Azure)
- Real-time analysis subjects and topics of 1.78 Billion tweets in 48h during Trump-Clinton debates.

REFERENCE

Sylvain Morice

Norbert Witzel

OVHcloud / Program Director

AMADEUS / Product Manager